<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-12-24T18:44:08+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Ali’s Stupid Blog</title><subtitle>Welcome to my stupid blog! Read the about me page to know me more!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Why I switched to a feature phone</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/24/why-I-switched-to-a-feature-phone.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I switched to a feature phone" /><published>2022-12-24T00:00:00+04:00</published><updated>2022-12-24T00:00:00+04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/12/24/why-I-switched-to-a-feature-phone</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/12/24/why-I-switched-to-a-feature-phone.html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello world, Some people have started to wonder why im less active on some mobile apps like telegram and stuff</p>

<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>TLDR</td>
      <td>I switched to a feature phone, not because of a smartphone addiciton just like most of these lifestyle influencers on youtube with their “why I switched to a dumb phone” videos, I switched to a feature phone because I barely use my smartphone but I do use it for Youtube and Signal only</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>NOTE</td>
      <td>I Will not call it a “Dumbphone” because its not dumb phone to begin with, But I will refer to it as a <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Feature_phone">Feature Phone</a></td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="reasoning">Reasoning</h2>

<p>at first I bought the <a href="https://www.gsmarena.com/energizer_energy_e241s-9569.php">Energizer e241s [1]</a> because it was the cheapest <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/KaiOS">KaiOS powered Phone</a> in my region, the original purpose of me buying this was because I wanted to mod the thing, I sure did mod it by a little but I am not going to talk about it in this blog post.</p>

<p>When it arrived ironically the first thing I did was move my SD and Sim Card to the phone because I will be comepletely honest, I don’t use my smartphone much other than using it for signal, whatsapp, and youtube when im on the go, but KaiOS does support whatsapp so thats crossed off the list, I still needed my phone for signal and youtube for when I am OTG [2]</p>

<h2 id="current-experience">Current Experience</h2>
<p>it has been 4 days since I used this as my main mobile device, and so far I have no problems with it, I am very quick when it comes to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/T9_(predictive_text)">T9 typing</a> so this isn’t a big problem of mine, infact im faster at typing on a keypad (with or without predictive text on) than on a touch screen, its wild, I really wish if there was a QWERTY KaiOS based phone, however I couldn’t find anything in my region aside form a phone from Mexico and the Jio Phone 2 [3]</p>

<p>Thats really about it for the blog, its pretty short but its something, if you spot any spelling errors make sure to fix them at the <a href="https://github.com/planetjunkie/planetjunkie.github.io">website repo</a> in the posts section, but that’s about it.</p>

<p>Ali signing off! :D</p>

<h3 id="numerical-references">Numerical references</h3>

<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>1</td>
      <td>this GSM arena article mentions the older unit, im using the 2021 revision with a faster processor and stuff</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>2</td>
      <td>OTG stands for on the go</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>3</td>
      <td>Jio Phone 2 is a mobile phone by the indian telecom Company which runs KaiOS</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Hello world, Some people have started to wonder why im less active on some mobile apps like telegram and stuff]]></summary></entry></feed>